Life is about to get hairier.
Tangled: Before Ever After is a adventure, animation,
comedy film directed by Tom Caulfield.
Rapunzel grapples with the responsibilities of being a
princess and the overprotective ways of her father.
While she wholeheartedly loves Eugene, Rapunzel does not share his immediate
desire to get married and settle down within the castle walls.
Determined to live life on her own terms, she and her tough-as-nails Lady-in-Waiting Cassandra embark on a secret
adventure where they encounter mystical rocks that magically cause Rapunzel's long blonde hair to grow back.
Impossible to break and difficult to hide, Rapunzel must learn
to embrace her hair and all that it represents.
Rapunzel (voice), played by Mandy Moore.
Eugene Fitzherbert (voice), played by Zachary Levi.
Cassandra (voice), played by Eden Espinosa.
King Frederic (voice), played by Clancy Brown.
Queen Arianna (voice), played by Julie Bowen.
Lady Caine (voice), played by Laura Benanti.
Tangled: Before Ever After is a 2017 American animated fantasy film produced by Disney Television
Animation, that premiered on Disney Channel as a Disney Channel Original Movie.
It is a sequel to the Walt Disney Animation Studios film Tangled and takes place between the original 2010 film
and the short Tangled Ever After, and serves as the first episode to Rapunzel's Tangled Adventure.
It was directed by Tom Caulfield and Stephen Sandoval.
The film centers on Rapunzel's adjustments to the life of a princess, and the
mysterious return of her 70 feet (21 m) of magical, golden hair.
The film premiered on March 10, 2017, on Disney Channel.
It features two new songs, "Life After Happily Ever After" and "Wind in My Hair", from Alan
Menken and Glenn Slater, who together wrote the songs for the original film.
"Wind in My Hair" would go on to become the opening
theme of Rapunzel's Tangled Adventure.
Mandy Moore, Zachary Levi, and M.
Gainey reprise their roles from Tangled as Rapunzel, Eugene
Fitzherbert, and the Captain of the Guard, respectively.
It is the fourth animated Disney Channel Original Movie following Kim Possible Movie: So the Drama, The Proud Family Movie, and Phineas
and Ferb the Movie: Across the 2nd Dimension, and the first of them to be based on a Walt Disney Animation Studios film.
It is also the second Disney Channel Original Movie based on material from Walt
Disney Animation Studios, after the 2015 live-action film Descendants.
The film explores themes of princess, marriage
proposal, fairy tale, coronation, hair.
The tone is lighthearted.